#### YANN MARCOU

#### Senior Full-stack Developer



CANADA



(514) 575-5443



yann17.marcou@gmail.com



https://creativeyann17.github.io





### **SKILLS & KNOWLEDGE**

#### Front-end



## Back-end



Spring-boot | Micronaut | JUnit | OpenAPI / Swagger

## Languages



Java | JavaScript | HTML / CSS / SCSS | C# | C/C++

#### Tools



IntelliJ | VSCode | Git | Github | Atlassian | npm | yarn | maven |

#### **Databases**



MongoDB | H2 | PostgreSQL | Oracle | Neo4j

# CI / CD / Cloud



Docker | Jenkins | Circle-ci | OpenShift | Heroku | Google Cloud | GitHub Actions



Arduino | Raspberry-pi

#### Extra



Tech lead | Shopify | Gimp | Blender | Agile methods







#### **ABOUT**

Hello, my name is Yann, French software developer. Until today I have worked on several personal / professional projects based on various kind of solutions: web, desktop and embedded. Different technologies were used like JAVA, JavaScript / HTML / CSS, C#, C/C++. I'm currently working abroad at Montreal.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Full-stack Developer

at CGI / Facilité (Montréal) from October 2017 to February 2021

Context: CGI from May 2018 to February 2021

Description: In continuity of Facilité (full-stack web developer) + tech lead of the dev team, in charge of:

- code review + good practices (clean code)
- conception / analyze of new features
- production releases deployment / support

Context: Facilité from October 2017 to May 2018

Description: Full-stack web developer for an important Banking company using the best of today's web technologies.

Technologies: Java 8 / 11, Spring-boot, JUnit, Docker, OpenShift, Swagger, React.js, GraphQL, JS / TS / HTML / CSS

Environment: GitFlow, continuous integration, deployment and support of production env. MacOS, Visual Code, IntelliJ, Agile methods, npm, maven

# Analyst programmer at ATOS (Toulouse) from March 2011 to October 2017

Context: January 2016 to October 2017

Description: Full stack development of a web application (database, controller, model, view) which centralizes several sources of avionic maintenance reports in order to identify and provide support + prevention for airline companies fleets of aircraft by analyzing trends and relations between failures.

Technologies: Play Framework 1.2.7, H2, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, JAVA, JavaScript, SQL, XML, JSON, JQuery 1.x.x, vis.js, Angular 1.x, Bootstrap 3.x

Environment: Agile method (Scrum/Sprint), Cytoscape, Eclipse, Gimp, Inkscape

Context: During 2015

Description: Development and testing of an XML periodic console application validator according to an XSD structure and internal checks. Once validated the model is inserted into database.

Technologies: C#, ZeroMQ, XML, XSD, Unit Tests, SQL Server, Visual Studio 2013, DotNET v4

Context: March 2011 to December 2014

Description: International Projects of R&D avionics maintenance. Development and integration of real-time applications on CPM POSIX / A653. Maintenance and





@CreativeYann17 🗹

## Linkedin

yann-marcou-21280267 🗹

prototyping of real-time applications in avionics simulation software and standalone tools used as script or model editor/validation.

Technologies: C/C++, STL, JAVA (J2SE, SWING, APPLET), Neo4J, GCC, GDB, XML, Visual Studio, POSIX, Cygwin, A653, Cytoscape

## **EDUCATION**

2007 - 2010 Master's degree in Engineering at ENSISA Mulhouse France

2005 - 2007 DUT (two-year technical degree in technology) Networks and Telecommunications at IUT (university institute of technology) Nancy-Brabois France

2002 - 2005 BAC scientific option engineering sciences at Lycée Marcel-Dassault France

#### **HOBBY**







